Matheus Vieira Portela

SQN 214 bl. J apt. 110 • Brasília, DF • 70.873-100 • +55 (61) 9273-9834 http://www.matheusportela.com • http://www.linkedin.com/in/matheusportela http://www.github.com/matheusportela • matheus.v.portela@gmail.com

PROFILE

A motivated student passionate by computer systems. Possesses strong communication skills and leadership experiences as a Scout Leader and as the Robot Soccer Team coordinator. International experiences include an exchange program to Australia and being the representative of the Brazilian Scouts in Sweden the United Arab Emirates.

EDUCATION

University of Brasília, Brazil Mechatronics Engineering

Mar 2010 – Dec 2015

GPA: 4.21/5

Relevant coursework: Computer Organization and Architecture, Systems Software, Operating Systems, Data Transmission, Computational Fundaments of Robotics, Probabilistic Robotics, Hydraulic and Pneumatic Systems, Integrated Manufacturing Systems, Industrial Organization, Real-Time Processing, Introduction to Game Development.

Australian National University

Jul 2012 - Jul 2013

Exchange Program

Science Without Borders program, sponsored by the Brazilian government.

Relevant coursework: Algorithms, Statistical Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Vision, Control Systems, Digital Communications, Signal Processing.

EXPERIENCE

IPe Network Engineering, Brazil

Iun 2014 – current

Intern - Operations and product development

- Analyzed possible clients for selling security solutions, such as firewall, IDS and WAF appliances.
- Analyzed and selected network security applications for product development support.
- Developed analysis methodology for vulnerability assessment and elaborated technical reports.
- Benchmarked in-development product prices and features.

University of Brasília, Brazil

Aug 2013 - Apr 2014

Undergraduate Researcher – Economics department

• Designed an algorithm for automatic identification of market sentiment with financial papers by crawling more than 10,000 tweets a day, identifying influential users and implementing machine learning, with about 60% accuracy.

CSIRO, Australia *Dec 2012 – Feb 2013*

Summer Intern – Autonomous systems laboratory

- Developed correction methodology for misrecognized words in speech recognition systems using gaze trackers, 35% faster than usual methods.
- Designed controlled experiments with 20 users, collected and analyzed data.
- Wrote and submitted scientific paper to an international conference.

LANGUAGES

Fluent: Portuguese, English. Intermediate: French, Spanish.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, C, C++, MATLAB, MIPS/x86 assembly, Git, LaTeX, Makefile. **Miscellaneous:** TCP/IP, Computer Networks, Network Security, MS Office, AutoCAD, Adobe Photoshop, Linux, Mac OS X, Windows.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- **Scout** since 2004, awarded with the Golden Lis Award (highest degree).
- Robot soccer team coordinator in 2014.
- **Assistant-director** and participant at Model UN.
- **MOOCs** participant in the following courses: Economics 101, Model Thinking, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Networks, Web Application Architectures, The Data Scientist's Toolbox, and R Programming.
- Honorable mention in Introduction to Game Development class.